mylookout.com 2013-11-06

# Privacy Policy - Lookout

###  LOOKOUT PRIVACY POLICY

Effective Date: May 21, 2013

A lot of companies say they care about your privacy — we say it and mean it!

This document is our Privacy Policy, which describes what information we collect from you and how we use it. Our Privacy Policy applies to our website at www.lookout.com, our mobile website, our mobile application Lookout Mobile Security, and all other services Lookout provides. It covers personally identifiable information (“PII”) which is information we can link to you personally. PII includes data like your name, email address, phone number, or mobile device’s unique identifier.

This Privacy Policy is part of the Lookout Terms of Use. By continuing to use our Services, you agree to be bound by both policies, so please read them carefully. Please contact us at [privacy@lookout.com](mailto:privacy@lookout.com) if you have any questions about this Privacy Policy.

  1. We Only Collect Your Personal Information When We Need It To Provide You a Service
  2. Information Lookout Collects
  3. What You Should Know About Specific Products
  4. Cookie Policy
  5. We Use Your PII to Provide and Improve Our Services
  6. Your Privacy is Not for Sale
  7. We Notify You if We Are Required by Law to Disclose Your PII
  8. We Share Your PII Where Necessary to Provide Our Services
  9. We Share Your PII to Avoid Unnecessary Marketing
  10. We Share Data That is Aggregated and Anonymized
  11. You Can Access and Update Your Privacy Settings
  12. Data Retention Policy
  13. You Can Permanently Delete Location Data at Any Time
  14. PII Posted to Our Blog and Community Forum Should Be Considered Public
  15. We Take Security Seriously
  16. You Are Responsible for Maintaining the Accuracy and Confidentiality of Your Email Address and Password
  17. International Visitors and Safe Harbor Compliance
  18. You Need a Parent’s Permission to Use Lookout if You Are Under 13
  19. We Are Not Responsible for Content on Third-Party Websites
  20. This Privacy Policy Will Apply Upon Change in Control
  21. We Post Updates on Our Website Whenever This Policy Changes
  22. Contact Us if You Have Any Questions or Concerns

####  1\. We Only Collect Your Personal Information When We Need It To Provide You A Service.

We are committed to only collecting the information necessary to provide and improve the Lookout Services. When we do collect your information, we store it and associate it with your account unless otherwise noted. We take your privacy very seriously and will only use and disclose this information under the terms described in this Privacy Policy.

Note that some of our products, like Lookout Labs, which are standalone products,  collect only limited information or no information at all. Not every section of this Privacy Policy will apply to these products.

####  2\. Information Lookout Collects

#####  a. Registration Information

To create an account, you must provide your email address and a password. You may also enter your mobile phone number on our website to initiate a text message with directions on how to download the app and register.

#####  b. Credit Card Information

If you wish to upgrade to a Premium Account billed directly to us, we collect your credit card number, expiration date, and security code. We use this information to bill you for services.

#####  c. Device Information

When you use Lookout Services, our servers automatically record certain information about your mobile device. This information may include information such as an equipment identifier (e.g., IMEI, UDID), subscriber identifier (e.g., IMSI), device name, mobile phone number, device type and manufacturer, operating system type and version, wireless carrier / operator, network type, country of origin, Internet Protocol (“IP”) address, and the dates and times of your requests. We use this information to provide our services. For example, collecting your device’s phone number allows the service to contact your phone via SMS when you locate your phone from the Lookout web application.

#####  d. Employment Application Information

If you wish to fill out our application form, we will ask for your name, email address, phone number, and allow you to upload your resume. We use this information to determine if you are an eligible candidate for an available position, to contact you to set up an interview if appropriate and to follow up with you about your application experience.

#####  e. Social Media Features

Our website includes social media Features (“Features”), like the Facebook recommend button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. If you use these Features, they will collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Features may be hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing the Feature, not by Lookout’s Privacy Policy.

#####  f. Information About Your Use of Lookout Services on Your Phone

We use mobile analytics software so that we can improve our products. This software may record information such as how often you use the application, the events that occur within the application, and where the application was downloaded. We do not link the information we store within the analytics software to any personally identifiable information you submit within the mobile app.

#####  g. Information About Your Use of Lookout’s Website and Mobile Website

We use an analytics service to measure how people use our website so that we can improve our products and services. The analytics service works by embedding invisible images that are associated with unique identifiers on our site. We do not tie the information gathered through the use of clear images to our customers’ personally identifiable information.

####  3\. What You Should Know About Specific Products

#####  a. Security and Anti-Virus

Lookout Security and Anti-Virus products, which are available on different platforms, protect your device from malware and spyware. They scan files and applications as they are installed or accessed, automatically scan your entire device periodically, and regularly update your threat definitions. In order to perform these functions, we need to collect information about the applications and files present on your device, the results of any scans performed by our services, and actions you take as a result of scanning. This may include downloading entire copies of files to your device (though you can opt out of this feature and still use the Anti-Virus product).

What types of information Security and Anti-Virus collect:

  * Information about the type of device you are using and the operating system you are running.
  * Lookout’s Security and Anti-Virus products collect information about the type of device and operating system you are running so that we can both improve our products and also give you more accurate information about malware and spyware that might affect you and your device(s).

  * Information about scans and scan results.
  * We collect information about the applications on your device in order to conduct scans and to download copies of scanned files, if you have not opted out of that functionality. We also may collect information about how applications behave on your device (e.g., whether an application is sending premium-rate text messages that charge money to your phone bill) and the network services with which your applications communicate, in order to determine if any applications are behaving maliciously (e.g., whether an application is talking to a server known to host phishing websites). Each time Lookout performs a scan, we collect information that describes what files and applications are identified by the scan as potentially undesirable and your choice for remediation of those files (e.g., uninstall or ignore).

How the information that Security and Anti-Virus collect is used:

Our purpose in collecting application data and security scan data is to provide you with Security and Anti-Virus services. We also use this data to optimize and improve this and other Lookout Services and products.

We may aggregate your data with other customers’ data in non-personally identifiable, aggregated, and anonymized form to better understand current malware and spyware threats and to improve the Anti-Virus service. We may also share this anonymous aggregated data publicly, in order to help others understand mobile threats and gain insights into particular mobile applications.

#####  b. Backup

Lookout Backup securely stores copies of data that you choose to back up from your phone.

What types of information Backup collects:

  * Backup Data.
  * Backup transmits a copy of the data you choose to back up to on your device to a secure server, using an encrypted protocol. The data may include your contacts, call history, pictures and other data. Lookout Backup automatically backs up your data weekly or daily, based on your settings, can restore your data to a new or existing phone, and allows you to retrieve your data any time from Lookout.com.

  * How the information that Backup collects is used:
  * If you choose to use the Lookout Backup feature, we will use the data you provide to deliver the Backup service. In order to notify you in the case of malicious behavior on your phone, Lookout may scan both the data that is stored on your phone and backed up to our servers. For example, some malware has been known to spread via malicious text messages or steal money by dialing expensive phone numbers. To detect this, our system would scan the SMS messages or call history stored on your phone or backed up on our servers.

#####  c. Missing Device

Lookout Missing Device helps you find and secure your phone or tablet if it is lost or stolen. You can locate your phone on a map using location information provided by your phone, activate a loud siren even if your volume is muted so that you can find a phone lost nearby, wipe your phone, or lock your phone. Features and settings are controlled through our website at Lookout.com.

What types of information Missing Device collects:

  * Location Data.
  * Lookout derives location information in two ways. We may receive it directly from your mobile device, or, in some situations, we may receive location data from cell tower or Wi-Fi hotspot information. We may use third-party service providers to translate that information into usable location information.

How the information that Missing Device collects is used:

Our purpose in collecting this information is to provide you with the location of your phone when you request it. If you activate the locate feature in Missing Device, your browser will send location information to Google Maps in order to display a map of the location within your Lookout account webpage. When activating this feature, we track the phone’s location for several minutes in order to provide an accurate location for you. This information is retained in your account history for as long as you wish and may be deleted by you at any time, from your account settings. If you choose to delete this information or disable your account, Lookout anonymizes this data so that it is no longer associated with an any personally identifiable information. We keep that anonymized data for aggregate statistical purposes only.

#####  d. Signal Flare

Signal Flare collects and stores information in the same way as Missing Device (see above). If you have enabled Signal Flare, it collects location information and sends it back to Lookout only when your battery is running low.  After which, we save the phone's location at the time we received the low battery alert to Lookout.com. This feature will help you locate your phone near its last known location if you lose it and its battery dies.

#####  e. Safe Browsing

Safe Browsing is a feature available when using the Android default browser or the Chrome browser.  Safe Browsing identifies and warns you of unsafe websites so that you can choose to avoid visiting them.

What types of information Safe Browsing collects:

  * URLs.
  * To provide the Safe Browsing service, we may transmit the URLs you visit on your phone to a Lookout-provided or third-party service to determine if those URLs are unsafe (e.g., if the URLs contain phishing attacks, malwares, or exploits). If a URL you visit is determined to be unsafe, we store a record of the unsafe URL.

How the information that Safe Browsing collects is used:

We use the record of unsafe URLs you visit (1) to provide you with notice that you attempted to reach an unsafe site (e.g., when you log in to the Lookout website or via email) and (2) to improve our product. If you do not want us to record the unsafe URLs you visit, you may turn Safe Browsing off; all other Lookout features will continue to function.

#####  f. Lock Cam

Lookout's Lock Cam feature uses your device’s camera and location features to help you figure out where your device might be (and who might have it) in the event that your device is lost or stolen. If activated, Lock Cam monitors when your password has been entered incorrectly a few times on your device or our app’s lock screen. It then activates your device’s camera remotely, without sound or other notification, and sends the resulting picture and its GPS coordinates to the email address associated with your account. For example, if someone steals your phone and fails to enter your password at least three times, Lock Cam could allow you to see what they look like and figure out where they are without alerting them.

What types of information Lock Cam collects:

  * Password and technical data.
  * In addition to the photographic and location information described above, Lock Cam keeps track of how frequently an incorrect password is entered.

How the information that Lock Cam collects is used:

When Lock Cam is activated and a photo is taken, the picture and location data are stored briefly on our servers so we can send you an email with the picture and a map of your device’s location. The picture and location data are then deleted. We send the email to the address associated with your account (or for Group Plans, to the address associated with the device that took the photo), so remember to keep your email address up to date in your account settings. We use technical information about Lock Cam’s activities on your device only to study, optimize, and troubleshoot our products.

#####  g. Group Plans

Group Plans link multiple devices to one master account that controls the Group Plan owner’s device as well as certain features of devices associated with the Group Plan. Users of the additional devices on the plan retain their own unique accounts, but Group Plan owners have control over some functions of Group Plan members’ devices, as described below.

What types of information Group Plans collect:

  * Lookout does not collect any additional information from users in Group Plans.

How the information that Group Plans collects is used:

In a Group Plan, such as a Family Plan, one master user has authority to perform certain functions on devices belonging to other members of the group. For example, in a Family Plan, a parent phone may be able to lock, wipe, restore, or locate a child’s phone. The latter feature would allow a parent to access data about the child’s phone as described in the section on “Missing Device.” A parent phone, or other device having authority over other Group Plan users, generally does not have access to the data on a child’s phone unless, for example, the phone is restored to another device to which the parent phone has access.

Users must agree to give the “parent” this functionality. You can determine if your phone is part of a Group Plan by checking the settings functions in your phone.

Lookout does not share any personally identifiable information collected from use of the Lookout Services in Group Plans with its partners, except as otherwise described in this policy..

####  4\. Cookie Policy

Like many online services, we use cookies and other tools to collect and analyze information about you and your usage of our Services. Cookies are small data files that we transfer to your computer. We use “session” cookies to keep you logged in while you use our Services, to better understand how you interact with our Services, and to monitor aggregate usage and web traffic information on our Services. Session cookies disappear when you log out and close your browser. We also use “persistent” cookies to recognize you when you return to our Services. Persistent cookies can stay on your computer for a longer period of time than session cookies do.

Most Internet browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can change your settings or use third-party tools to refuse cookies or prompt you before accepting cookies from the websites you visit. You can also use your browser settings or other tools to delete cookies you already have. Please be aware that some parts of our Services may not work for you if you disable cookies.

#####  Cookies From Third-Parties

We believe it is important for you to know exactly what cookies we use in our Services. Here is a list of the third-party cookies that we use, a link to the privacy policy governing the cookie and information about how you can opt out.

**Google Analytics** — This cookie allows us to see how you use our website and mobile application so that we can improve your experience. We encourage you to read the [Google Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/).

If you don’t want data reported by Google Analytics, you can install the [Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptou).

**Optimizely** — This cookie allows us to optimize the look, feel and messaging of our website based upon how you use it. You can read the [Optimizely Privacy Policy here](https://www.optimizely.com/privacy) and [opt out here](https://www.optimizely.com/opt_out). 

**Jobvite** — This cookie is used to provide you with a personalized user experience when you apply for a job with us. You can read the [Jobvite Privacy Policy here](http://recruiting.jobvite.com/privacy-policy/). 

**AdRoll** — This cookie allows us to present you with retargeting advertising  on other sites based on your previous interaction on our website. The [AdRoll Privacy Policy](http://www.adroll.com/about/privacy) explains how their cookie works and gives you the option to adjust or opt out of this program. 

**AddThis** — The social sharing site creates and reads this JavaScript on the client side in order to make sure the user sees the updated count if they share a page and return to it before our share count cache is updated. No data from that cookie is sent back to AddThis and removing it when disabling cookies would cause unexpected behavior for users.

If you prefer not to use any cookies, you can also opt out in some browsers by turning on “Do Not Track” or visit <http://www.aboutads.info/choices/> to opt out directly.

####  5\. We Use Your Personally Identifiable Information to Provide and Improve Our Services

We limit our internal use of your information to providing services that enhance our products and help you use them. For example:

  * If you fill out a survey or email Lookout for support, we will retain the information you give us in order to provide you with support and to improve our Services.
  * Where available, Lookout may use client device information to let you know you need to update your operating system.
  * We may share encrypted (hashed) equipment identifier numbers with analytics services to understand how new users find out about our application.
  * We may send text messages to your phone to communicate with your device.
  * We may use your email address or mobile number for administrative purposes, such as sending privacy or security related notices, notifying you of major Lookout Services changes, to contact you regarding product announcements such as special promotions or new products and services, or for other customer service purposes.

You can choose to opt out of receiving emails or notices from us at any time by logging into your web account and changing your account preferences, or by clicking the unsubscribe button/link at the bottom of our emails.

####  6\. Your Privacy is Not for Sale

Lookout will not sell any personally identifiable information we collect from you. Period.

####  7\. We Notify You if we Are Required by Law to Disclose Your Personally Identifiable Information

Like other companies, we may be required to preserve or disclose your information if after due consideration, we determine it is necessary to comply with a law, regulation, or legal request; to protect the safety of any person; to address fraud, security, or technical issues; or to protect Lookout’s rights or property. However, we strongly believe that you have a right to know when we will respond to a request for your information in time to give you the opportunity to object.  Therefore, it is our policy to notify you at the email listed in your account of a request for your information before we preserve or disclose it, unless we are legally prohibited from doing so. Furthermore, nothing in this Privacy Policy is meant to limit any legal defenses or objections that you may have to a third party’s, including the government’s request to disclose your information.

####  8\. We Share Your Personally Identifiable Information When Necessary to Provide Our Services

We only use your Personal Information to improve our services. This may include sharing aspects of your Personal Information with 3rd parties (for example, to map your location or send you an SMS).  We require that these parties agree to process such information in compliance with our Privacy Policy, that they use reasonable efforts to limit their use of such information, and that they use appropriate confidentiality and security measures to protect your information.

####  9\. We Share Your Personally Identifiable Information to Avoid Unnecessary Marketing

In order to prevent you from receiving duplicate or unnecessary marketing about Lookout products or service, we may share your status as a current Lookout customer with our partners or service providers.  They are contractually prevented from using this information for any other purpose.

####  10\. We Share Data That is Aggregated and Anonymized

We share anonymized, aggregated data with partners or in security reports. This information is never associated with Personal Identifiable Information and cannot be identified with you. For example, we may store a count of the number of devices that have ever encountered a particular piece of malware.

####  11\. You Can Access and Update Your Privacy Settings

Both the Lookout website and the Lookout ‘Settings’ on your device have options that allow you to update or modify your privacy settings at any time. To protect your privacy and security, we require your username and password in order to verify your identity before granting you profile access or making changes.  If your email address changes, you may update your information within the Lookout website. Simply go to the “Account” page and select the information you wish to update. If you wish to correct or delete inaccuracies within your personal information, or to request access to any personal information we obtain about you, please contact us at [privacy@lookout.com](mailto:privacy@lookout.com). We will respond to your request to access within 30 days.

####  12\. Data Retention Policy

It is our policy to retain data indefinitely. We regularly perform data backups to protect your data during maintenance of our production servers. When you use the Dashboard to delete Backup data or to deactivate your account, that data will no longer be accessible through your account. However, it may remain on our production servers to enable you to reactivate your account or to recover accidentally deleted data. If you have accidentally deleted data from your account, you should contact [support@lookout.com](mailto:support@lookout.com) as soon as possible, so we can try to recover it.

####  13\. You Can Permanently Delete Location Data At Any Time

When you delete location data through your account dashboard on Lookout.com, it is no longer linked to your account and is anonymized on our production systems. Your location data is irretrievably removed from any identifiable information you’ve provided to Lookout. 

####  14\. Personally Identifiable Information Posted to Our Blog and Community Forum Should be Considered Public

If you comment on the blog, you should be aware that any personally identifiable information you submit there can be read, collected, or used by other users of those blogs, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose to submit in these blogs or for any content you receive as a result of sharing such information.

To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, contact us at [privacy@lookout.com](mailto:privacy@lookout.com). If we are not able to remove your personal information, we will let you know why.

####  15\. We Take Security Seriously

Lookout is a security company, and securing your data is one of our top priorities. Lookout uses commercially reasonable physical, managerial, and technical safeguards. For example, we use a combination of firewalls, encryption, authentication, physical security, and other safeguards to protect your account and your data.

We perform third-party penetration tests to harden our systems from attack. We cannot, however, ensure or warrant the security of any information that Lookout receives on your behalf to operate the Lookout Services, or information that you transmit to Lookout. All such receipt or transmission of your information is at your own risk.

We cannot guarantee that such information will not be accessed, disclosed, altered, or destroyed by breach of any of our physical, technical, or managerial safeguards.

The security of your personal information is important to us. When you enter sensitive information (such as credit card number or location based information) on our website, within the Lookout app, or in our order forms, we encrypt that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL).

If Lookout learns of a security systems breach, we may attempt to notify you electronically so that you can take appropriate protective steps. Lookout may also post a notice on the Lookout Services if a security breach occurs. Depending on where you live, you may have a legal right to receive notice of a security breach in writing.

####  16\. You Are Responsible for Maintaining the Accuracy and Confidentiality of Your Email Address and Password

You are responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your password at all times. We recommend a strong password that you do not use with other services. If you believe your password has been compromised, please change your password immediately via the Lookout website, or contact us at [support@lookout.com](mailto:support@lookout.com) for assistance.

You are responsible for ensuring that the email address associated with your account is accurate. We use that email to contact you about service updates, changes to our policies, and account activities such as requests for your information or locate attempts on your device.  Lookout is not responsible for personal data transmitted to a third party as a result of a user’s providing an incorrect email address.

####  17\. International Visitors and Safe Harbor Compliance

Lookout is a San Francisco-based company with servers housed in the United States. Personal information collected from users outside the United States is transferred to the United States and processed according to United States law.

Lookout complies with the U.S. – E.U. Safe Harbor Framework and the U.S. – Swiss Safe Harbor framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal data from European Union member countries and Switzerland. Lookout has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view Lookout's’s certification, please visit <http://export.gov/safeharbor>.

####  18\. You Need a Parent’s Permission to Use Lookout if You Are Under 13

Lookout does not knowingly collect or store any personal information about children under the age of 13 unless they are part of a Group Plan purchased by a parent who consents to such collection and storage as described in the Lookout Terms of Service. If you believe a child is using this service without parental consent, please contact us at [privacy@lookout.com](mailto:privacy@lookout.com).

####  19\. We Are Not Responsible for Content on Third-Party Websites

Our site contains links to other websites. When you click on one of these links, you leave Lookout’s website and go elsewhere. Lookout does not accept liability for misuse of any information by any website controller to which we may link. We encourage you to read the privacy statements of these linked sites, which may differ from ours. In addition, if you take advantage of an offer from one of our partners, you may be providing information directly to that partner. We encourage you to review the privacy statements of these partners as we are not responsible for the privacy practices of any partners or linked sites.

####  20\. This Privacy Policy Will Apply Upon Change in Control

In the event that Lookout is involved in a bankruptcy, merger, acquisition, reorganization, or sale of assets, your information may be sold or transferred as part of that transaction. The promises in this Privacy Policy will apply to your information as transferred to a new entity.

####  21\. We Post Updates on Our Website Whenever This Policy Changes

This Privacy Policy may be revised. If we make material changes to this policy, then we will notify you in our application, here on this website, by email, or by means of a notice on the Lookout Services home page.

####  22\. Contact Us if You Have Any Questions or Concerns

Please contact our privacy manager at [privacy@lookout.com](mailto:privacy@lookout.com), or by postal mail at Lookout, Inc., One Front Street, Suite 2700, San Francisco, CA 94111, with any questions or comments about this privacy policy. We will respond to your inquiry within 30 days of its receipt.

  * Effective as of May 21, 2013. Updated to (1) include that information submitted with an employment application is a type of PII that we collect, (2) include a section on Social Media Features, (3) inform that Lookout may share PII in to prevent its customers from receiving unnecessary marketing, (4) include a section explaining information collection and use as it relates to the “Signal Flare” feature, (5) clarify use of cookies, (6) assure that, unless we are legally prohibited from doing so, Lookout will notify users of a request for information, (7) clarify data storage, and (8) assure that the Privacy Policy will continue to control information if Lookout ever experiences a change in control. 
  * Effective as of December 13, 2012. Updated to include section on Lock Cam. 
  * Effective as of October 1, 2012.  Updated to (1) include section on Group Plans, (2) clarify use of cookies, and (3) permit use by children with parent’s consent as part of Group Plan. 
  * Effective January 12, 2012.  Updated to clarify that unique device identifier (UDID) is a subset of equipment identifier that may be recorded on our servers when you use the Lookout Services, and to clarify our policy regarding the removal of personal information from blogs and community forums.
  * Effective as of June 15, 2011.  Updated to include Safe Browsing and Lookout Security.
  * Effective as of October 18, 2011.  Updated to clarify that the device type and OS version are collected as part of the Security and Anti-Virus features and add that hashed equipment identifiers are shared to understand how new users find Lookout.
  * Original policy effective as of May 8, 2009.
